<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Readings on CS7210 - Distributed Computing</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/</link><description>Recent content in Readings on CS7210 - Distributed Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>W02 - Logical Time</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w02_logical_time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w02_logical_time/</guid><description>A Way to Capture Causality in Distributed Systems Link to Paper
This paper is an easy read and not very long. Moreover, first few pages just repeat the same thing over and over. So, you can read through it in a couple of hours.
Big Ideas
Global/physical clocks don’t work for distributed processes. So, we use a system of logical clocks where each process has its own clock.</description></item><item><title>W03 - Consistent Global States</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w03_consistent_global_states/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w03_consistent_global_states/</guid><description>Consistent Global States of Distributed Systems Fundamental Concepts and Mechanisms Link to Paper
1 Introduction What is global state of a distributed system?
It is the union of the states of the individual processes.
Why do we study construction of global state?
A large class of problems in distributed computing can be cast as executing some action when the state of the system satisfies a particular condition.</description></item><item><title>W07 - Spanner</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w07spanner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w07spanner/</guid><description>Spanner FAQ Source: MIT 6.824 - Distributed Systems &amp;gt; Spanner FAQs
Q: What is time? A: 13:00:00.000 April 7th 2020 UTC is a time. Time advances at a steady rate of one second per second. Q: What is a clock? A: A clock is an oscillator driving a counter. The oscillator should tick at a steady known rate (e.g. one tick per second). The counter must initially be synchronized to a source of the correct time; after that, the oscillator's ticks cause the counter to advance the time.</description></item></channel></rss>