<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Readings on CS7210 - Distributed Computing</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/</link><description>Recent content in Readings on CS7210 - Distributed Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>L03 - Logical Time</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w02_logical_time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w02_logical_time/</guid><description>Logical Time: A Way to Capture Causality in Distributed Systems - M. Raynal, M. Singha
A Way to Capture Causality in Distributed Systems Link to Paper
This paper is an easy read and not very long. Moreover, first few pages just repeat the same thing over and over. So, you can read through it in a couple of hours.
Big Ideas
Global/physical clocks don’t work for distributed processes.</description></item><item><title>L04 - Consistent Global States</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w03_consistent_global_states/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w03_consistent_global_states/</guid><description>Consistent Global States of Distributed Systems Fundamental Concepts and Mechanisms Link to Paper
1 Introduction What is global state of a distributed system?
It is the union of the states of the individual processes.
Why do we study construction of global state?
A large class of problems in distributed computing can be cast as executing some action when the state of the system satisfies a particular condition.</description></item><item><title>W07 - Amazon Aurora</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/07_amazon_aurora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/07_amazon_aurora/</guid><description>Amazon Aurora: On Avoiding Distributed Consensus for I/Os, Commits, and Membership Changes - Alexandre Verbitski, Anurag Gupta, Debanjan Saha, James Corey, Kamal Gupta Murali Brahmadesam, Raman Mittal, Sailesh Krishnamurthy, Sandor Maurice Tengiz Kharatishvilli, Xiaofeng Bao
Links The Morning Paper
Just How &amp;ldquo;Global&amp;rdquo; is Amazon Aurora? - CockroachLabs
Notes on Amazon Aurora
diegopacheco/notes
https://www.binwang.me/2020-09-16-Aurora-Database.html</description></item><item><title>W07 - Spanner</title><link>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w07spanner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.digestnotes.com/readings/w07spanner/</guid><description>Links Spanner and Open Source Implementations OSDI12 - Spanner: Google’s Globally-Distributed Database - Youtube Spanner FAQ Source: MIT 6.824 - Distributed Systems &amp;gt; Spanner FAQs
Q: What is time? A: 13:00:00.000 April 7th 2020 UTC is a time. Time advances at a steady rate of one second per second. Q: What is a clock? A: A clock is an oscillator driving a counter.</description></item></channel></rss>